PRIVACY POLICY
==============

TeamSeas understands your concerns about privacy and your interest in knowing how your information is used and safeguarded, and we want to provide you with more information on these topics. This Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) describes the practices, policies and procedures related to the TeamSeas website located at www.teamseas.com (the “Website”), including the types of personal information we collect on the Website, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. This Website is owned and operated by MrBeastYouTube, LLC, (hereinafter referred to as “MrBeast,” or “we” or “us”). Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to the online information-gathering and sharing practices occurring on our Website, and does not apply to any of our practices conducted offline, or via other online channels. We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. The date this Privacy Policy was last updated is stated at the end of this document.

### SUMMARY

The notifications provided by this Privacy Policy include:

* What personally identifiable information we collect from you through the Website.
* How we use the information we collect.
* With whom the information may be shared.
* The kind of procedures we employ in an effort to hinder the unauthorized access, use or disclosure of information you provide to us.
* Information related to third-party websites.
* The laws that apply to those accessing our Website from outside of the United States.
* How you can learn about changes to our privacy policies, practices and procedures.
* Rights related to the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation

### THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

**Personal Information You Provide And How It Is Used:** You may freely visit our Website anonymously and without being required to provide us with any personal information. However, certain features do require that you provide us with some personally identifying information. Please note that we only collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us; personal information is data that can be used to identify you. Examples of instances in which we collect personal information include:

_Donate:_ If you make a donation through the Website via the “donate” button, you will be asked to provide certain personally identifying information as required by the payment processor for the payment method selected.

_Team Creation:_ If you opt to create a team to help raise donations, you will be asked to provide us with a “display” name and email address.

_E-Newsletter:_ If you opt to receive updates, we will ask you to provide your email address, first and last name.

_Shop:_ If you opt to buy an item from our online store, we will ask you to provide certain personally identifying information, such as your name and home address, as well as your payment information. Please note that we work with third parties to host and administer the shop, and to process your payment transactions, and any information you share will also be shared with such third parties.

**Non-Personal Information We Collect by Automated Means And How We Use It:** We also collect certain non-personal information (data in a form that does not support direct association with any specific person or individual) by automated means when you visit the Website. Much of this information is collected through the use of third-party tracking services, which includes Google Analytics and Hotjar. The information collected may include usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of users to the Website, pages visited, web browsing histories, your location and device, social networking activities and similar data. When gathered, this this data is used in the aggregate, and not in a manner that is intended to identify you personally. This type of aggregate information may be shared with third parties at any time, including marketers. In addition to the third-party tracking services mentioned above, we also collect this information through various other means, including "cookies,” as further explained below.

_Cookies:_ A cookie is a piece of information that a web server may place on your computer when you visit a Website. Cookies are commonly used by websites to improve the user experience. Many cookies last only through a single Website session, or visit. Others may have an expiration date, or may remain on your computer until you delete them. We may also use cookies for other purposes, including to maintain continuity during a user session, to gather data about the usage of our Website for research and other purposes, or to store a user name or related login credentials so that you do not have to provide this information every time you return to our Website.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookie/scripts, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie/script, and how to disable existing cookies. You can also increase your control over scripts and cookies with a multitude of browser plug-ins such as NoScript, Ghostery, Lightbeam and Do Not Track Plus. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all the features on our Website.

_IP Addresses_ - When you visit and interact with the Website, third parties with whom we have contracted to provide services for us may collect Internet Protocol addresses (each an "IP Address"), as well as browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and page navigation. An IP Address is a unique identifier number that certain electronic devices use to identify and to communicate with each other on the Internet; your Internet Service Provider automatically assigns an IP Address to the computer that you are using.

### HOW WE MAY SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

We may disclose all of the information (described herein) that we collect, as stated in this Privacy Policy including in accordance with the terms set forth in this section. Please note MrBeast works with a variety of third-party partners in order to allow us to make the Website available to you, to host and store the information we collect from you, and to provide certain functionality and features, such as to process payment/donation transactions, or to fulfill the orders you place with our online store. We will also share information related to your donation - for “transactional” purposes - with both the Ocean Conservancy and The Ocean Cleanup North Pacific Foundation, the two nonprofit organizations who are the recipients of the donations processed through the Website. Except as stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not reveal personally identifiable information about you to third parties for their independent use unless: (1) you expressly authorize MrBeast to do so, (2) it is necessary to allow MrBeast and its service providers or agents to provide services on MrBeast’s behalf, (3) it is to provide services to you, (4) it is disclosed to entities that perform marketing or data aggregation services for MrBeast, (5) it is necessary in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of MrBeast or the merger of MrBeast into another entity or any consolidation, share exchange, combination, reorganization, or like transaction in which MrBeast is not the survivor, (6) MrBeast is required or permitted to do so for any or all of the following reasons: (i) to comply with a subpoena, legal process, government request or any other legal obligation, (ii) to prevent, investigate, detect, or prosecute criminal offenses or attacks on the technical integrity of the Website or our network, and/or (iii) to protect the rights, privacy, property, business, or safety of MrBeast, its partners and employees, the visitors of the Website, the children or families that we serve, or the public.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Although we specifically require in our Terms of Use that anyone using our Website who is younger than 13 years of age first receive parental consent, we understand that children may still access the Website and provide us with information. In cases in which may collect, use, or disclose personally identifiable information about visitors to our Website that are less than 13 years of age, please note that we have a separate privacy disclosure statement to address our protocols related to such collection, located [HERE](https://teamseas.org/coppa-policy/). If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 13 years of age and you have any concerns related to the information we may be collecting and using, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://teamseas.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), and be sure to include in your message the same username and email address that your child submitted, if applicable.

### HOW WE ATTEMPT TO SAFEGUARD YOUR INFORMATION

We maintain – and ask that any third-party partners who may store information on our behalf to maintain - administrative, technical and physical safeguards for the Website designed to protect your personal information against theft, loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the personal information that we collect from you. We restrict access to personal information collected about you on the Website to our employees, our affiliates' employees, those who are otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy, or others who need to know such information to provide services to you or in the course of conducting our business operations or activities. However, no website, application or transmission can guarantee security. Thus, while we have established and maintain what we believe to be reasonable procedures to protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of personally identifying information obtained through the Website and we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.

### YOUR INFORMATION AND YOUR CHOICES

To the extent required by law, we provide you with reasonable access to the personally identifiable information you provide to us. Upon appropriate written request we will update or amend your information, but we reserve the right to use any information previously obtained to verify your identity or take other actions that we believe are appropriate and lawful. We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Please note we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes, and there may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed from such locations. Finally, please note that we are not responsible for removing or deleting information from the databases of third parties (such as service providers) with whom we have shared information about you.

### USE OF THE WEBSITE FROM OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES

We do not represent or warrant that the Website, or any part thereof, is appropriate or available for use in any particular geographic location. If you choose to access our Website, you do so on your own initiative and at your own risk, and are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules, and regulations applicable in your jurisdiction. Please note that the Website is hosted in the United States and is governed by United States law. If you are visiting the Website from outside the United States, please be aware that your information will be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By using the Website, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

### PRIVACY QUESTIONS AND CONTACTING US

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://teamseas.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check back regularly to see if there have been any changes to this policy, which you can determine by reviewing the Effective Date listed below. By continuing to use the Website after those changes become effective, you consent and agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

### SPECIAL NOTICE TO EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA, SWITZERLAND AND UNITED KINGDOM USERS

The following provisions applies only to users residing in the European Economic Area, Switzerland and the United Kingdom.

Pursuant to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), we are required to provide those residing in the European Economic Area, Switzerland and the United Kingdom (hereinafter, the “EU Users”) additional information and rights related to the “Personal Data” we collect about them. We summarize such information and rights below.

### HOW TO CONTACT US

MrBeastYouTube, LLC (the Data Controller) is the owner and operator of the Website. If you need to contact us for any reason related to this Privacy Policy or your use of the Website, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://teamseas.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or write to us at Legalese contact: 1300 19th St NW 8th floor, Washington, DC 20036.

### PURPOSE FOR INFORMATION COLLECTION

As noted in this Privacy Policy, you may visit our Website without being required to provide us with any Personal Data. However, should you decide to provide such information, the information we collect will be used to meet your requests, or to provide you with the applicable information or service requested, and as further described herein.

### LEGAL GROUNDS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL DATA

MrBeast will process personal data that we receive from EU Users on the ground that it is in our legitimate interest for the effective administration of the Website, to fulfill and/or address your requests, or to provide the functionalities and features as further described herein.

### YOUR INFORMATION AND YOUR CHOICES; WITHDRAWAL OF CONSENT

GDPR provides EU Users with additional rights in respect to the Personal Data we hold about you, including the right i) to be informed about the Personal Data we have collected, and ii) to request a copy of the Personal Data, and iii) to have your Personal Data deleted, and iv) to lodge a complaint about our processing of your Personal Data with your local supervisory authority. Upon appropriate written request we will update or amend your Personal Data, but we reserve the right to use any information previously obtained to verify your identity or take other actions that we believe are appropriate and lawful. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your Personal Data – or request that we stop any processing of your Personal Data - by contacting us at the address listed above. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

Please note we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes, and there may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed from such locations. Additionally, there may be circumstances in which we are not legally required to comply with your request because of the laws in your jurisdiction or because of exemptions provided in data protection legislation in general, and GDPR in particular. Finally, please note that we are not responsible for removing or deleting information from the databases of third parties (such as service providers) with whom we have shared information about you, but we will make the request on your behalf for such removal/deletion.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY/NOTE TO PARENTS OF CHILDREN RESIDING IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA, SWITZERLAND AND UNITED KINGDOM

Although we specifically require that anyone using our Website who is not of the required age to act on their own behalf in their jurisdiction/country (“children” or “child”) first receive parental consent, we understand that children may still access the Website and provide us with information. In cases in which we may collect, use, or disclose personally identifiable information about children to our Website, please note that we have a separate privacy disclosure statement to address our protocols related to such collection, located HERE. If you are the parent or guardian of a child and you have any concerns related to the information we may be collecting and using, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://teamseas.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), and be sure to include in your message the same username and email address that your child submitted, if applicable.

**PRIVACY POLICY EFFECTIVE DATE**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of October 27, 2021

FAQ

Contact Us

Press Inquiries

JOIN #TEAMSEAS

Every $1 is one less pound of trash in the ocean

### FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS

#### WHAT IS #TEAMSEAS?

[#TeamSeas](https://teamseas.org/) is a global campaign to raise $30M to remove 30M pounds of plastic and trash from our ocean, rivers and beaches. It’s also the second wave of the largest creator-led fundraising campaign to ever hit the internet: [#TeamTrees](https://teamtrees.org/). We launched [#TeamTrees](https://teamtrees.org/) in 2019 with a goal of raising $20M to plant 20M trees and we smashed it—raising over $23M and generating more than 1B video views. Even two years later, TeamTrees.org is still receiving donations and planting 2,600 trees every day. We’re back again to rally the internet’s passion and imagination in support of the ocean.

* * *

#### WHAT IS THE TIMING OF THE CAMPAIGN?

We launched #TeamSeas on Friday, October 29th at 1pm PT with a [massive wave of online videos](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23teamseas) and we’ll continue to create content to rally our communities throughout the campaign. (If you’re reading this right now, and you love the ocean, we invite you to create something too). The $30M fundraising goal officially ends on **January 1, 2022 at 11:59pm PT**, so we only have a short amount of time to raise the money. The funded cleanup work will begin in 2022 and is scheduled to conclude in three years. We’ll keep the site up and running the whole time (and you can still plant a tree at TeamTrees.org!).

* * *

#### WHAT HAPPENS TO THE MONEY?

_Every single dollar_ #TeamSeas raises toward the $30M will go to independently verified pounds of trash that have been removed from beaches, rivers or the ocean. When you donate, the funds go directly to the two not-for-profit organizations, Ocean Conservancy and The Ocean Cleanup. They split the funds 50/50 and the money will be released when the trash is removed and verified: $1, one pound. Each non-profit is responsible for delivering on their half of the goal.

* * *

#### WHAT HAPPENS TO THE TRASH?

Great question! Wherever and whenever possible, items like cans, glass, and plastic beverage bottles will be separated and recycled. In cases where contamination of the trash and/or lack of local recycling makes it impossible to reprocess, trash will go to a proper disposal site in accordance with local regulations and capacity. That’s why we need to reduce the amount of plastic we use and waste we generate, period.

* * *

#### WHO IS BEHIND #TEAMSEAS?

Just like the original campaign that inspired it, #TeamSeas is being led by [Mark](https://www.youtube.com/c/MarkRober/) (Rober), Jimmy ([MrBeast](https://www.youtube.com/c/MrBeast6000)) and Campaign Director, Matt Fitzgerald (@fitz350). We’ve reunited many of the world’s most popular content creators to help launch the campaign, add their creativity and invite their audience to power #TeamSeas toward its ambitious 30M goal. At the end of the day, we hope to create a platform that you—anyone reading this—can genuinely claim as your own. Think of it as a giant, global potluck for good. What would you like to bring to the party?

* * *

#### WHICH NONPROFIT ORGANIZATIONS ARE YOU PARTNERING WITH?

For #TeamSeas, we’ve partnered up with [Ocean Conservancy](https://oceanconservancy.org/) and [The Ocean Cleanup](http://theoceancleanup.com/). All donations to #TeamSeas will be split between the two organizations, 50/50.

[Ocean Conservancy](https://oceanconservancy.org/) is #TeamSeas’s implementation partner for beaches and oceans. Ocean Conservancy champions science-based solutions to tackle the largest ocean conservation challenges we face to strengthen the health of the ocean today and for the future. They mobilize citizen advocates to facilitate change, and are committed to supporting efforts that benefit the people who depend on the ocean for food, jobs and recreation. Ocean Conservancy facilitates the International Coastal Cleanup (ICC), one of the world’s largest volunteer cleanup efforts for the ocean. Ocean Conservancy is a US-based 501(c)(3) nonprofit (EIN 23-7245152) and is rated 4 stars (94/100) by Charity Navigator.

[The Ocean Cleanup](http://theoceancleanup.com/) is #TeamSeas’s implementation partner for rivers. The [Ocean Cleanup](http://theoceancleanup.com/) develops and scales technologies to clean up what is already polluting our oceans and to intercept plastic on its way to the ocean via rivers. Their goal is to achieve a 90% reduction of floating ocean plastic by 2040. Founded in 2013, The Ocean Cleanup has a proven commitment to the ambitious goal of ridding the world’s oceans of plastic. With their river systems, the Interceptors, they are now helping to close the tap on a global scale, capturing plastic before it enters the oceans via rivers. The Ocean Cleanup is a registered ANBI Foundation in the Netherlands, and their U.S. affiliate, The Ocean Cleanup North Pacific Foundation, is also a [Gold-rated](https://www.guidestar.org/profile/81-5132355#mission) US 501(c)(3) nonprofit (EIN 81-5132355).

* * *

#### WHAT’S THE DEAL WITH PLASTIC POLLUTION IN OUR WATER?

The ocean and the life within it are incredibly important. Aside from the water we drink, the ocean produces half the air we breathe every day. So it’s a no-brainer that keeping it clean and healthy is critical to our survival. Unfortunately our ocean—and the rivers that feed it—are full of plastic trash. It’s estimated that there are 200M tons of plastic already circulating in marine environments, with an estimated 11M tons entering the ocean EVERY YEAR. Pollution from items like bottles, bags, straws and abandoned fishing gear is a health crisis for our entire planet.

* * *

#### HOW ARE WE ACTUALLY GOING TO CLEAN UP ALL THIS TRASH?

We’re glad you asked. Because 30M pounds is A LOT of trash (roughly equivalent to 85 football fields covered a foot deep). We’re dividing our work among three points of intervention: beaches, rivers and oceans.

**Beaches**  
With the experts at Ocean Conservancy, we’ll send professional crews to clean up some of the most iconic, vulnerable beaches on the planet. We’ll also be holding safe, locally-hosted #TeamSeas events leveraging Ocean Conservancy’s International Coastal Cleanup (ICC) network so #TeamSeas supporters can roll up their sleeves and make an impact firsthand, one pound of trash at a time. The ICC is the largest beach cleanup network in the world (more than 350 million pounds of trash have been collected from beaches in its 35+ year history!)

**Rivers**  
For our rivers, #TeamSeas will fund Interceptors™, The Ocean Cleanup’s river cleanup technologies that collect trash before it can reach the ocean. The Ocean Cleanup has several Interceptors already deployed in some of the world’s most polluted rivers to catch plastic and trash upstream. #TeamSeas will support the expansion and continued operation of this work as The Ocean Cleanup takes aim at the 1% of rivers which contribute 80% of the trash flowing into the ocean from rivers.

**Oceans**  
Lost, abandoned and discarded fishing gear – or ghost gear – is some of the deadliest ocean trash, and is super tricky to recover. #TeamSeas will work with Ocean Conservancy’s Global Ghost Gear Initiative® to go to ghost gear “graveyards,” where we’ll identify and float the abandoned gear to the surface, hook it onto boat cranes and remove it from the ocean forever.

* * *

#### HOW CAN I HELP?

We want you to do what you do best. Talk to a friend, organize your school or business, make some art, film a video, whatever makes sense to you and your community as we work toward 30M. For #TeamTrees, we saw artists draw comics for trees, kids hold bakesales, and tech founders one-up each other on the Leaderboard. Whoever your team is, get them on #TeamSeas. You can create a Team during checkout or join one from Search.

We recommend you start by telling someone else about the mission, why you’re passionate about it, and invite them to get involved at TeamSeas.org. We also encourage you to engage with and amplify #TeamSeas content across the internet. We think you’ll be surprised at who else is on #TeamSeas and how many fascinating videos are out there for you to discover. As the campaign develops, we hope you’ll co-create it with us as we rally toward our shared 30M goal. One of the most exciting parts for us is that we have no idea what you’ll come up with, and we can’t wait to see it.

* * *

#### WHO SHOULD I TAG OR FOLLOW ON SOCIAL? WHAT’S OFFICIAL?

#TeamSeas official social accounts will always be listed here and on the homepage. If you’re not sure if it’s legit, check TeamSeas.org. Here’s the latest list:

Twitter: [twitter.com/teamseas](https://twitter.com/teamseas) , Instagram: [instagram.com/teamseas](https://instagram.com/teamseas) , Facebook: [facebook.com/teamseas](https://facebook.com/teamseas) , YouTube: [youtube.com/teamseas](https://youtube.com/teamseas) , reddit: [reddit.com/r/teamseas](https://reddit.com/r/teamseas) , TikTok: [tiktok.com/@teamseas](https://tiktok.com/@teamseas) ( use the ‘Support Nonprofit’ donate sticker for Ocean Conservancy). If you stream on Twitch, check out the TeamSeas campaign tools on Tiltify to let your viewers donate live and your community to fundraise together.

Speaking of legit, the only official store for #TeamSeas is [store.teamseas.org](https://store.teamseas.org/). Please watch out for scammers.

Last but not least, we encourage you to engage with other #TeamSeas supporters to weave together all our crazy internet worlds in support of the cause. Spread love, mash the RT button, and if you see a way to organize something cool together, well, that’s awesome!

* * *

#### IS CLEANUP REALLY THE BEST SOLUTION?

The plastic pollution problem is so big that no single solution will fix it at once. But we’ve got to start somewhere. 30M pounds of trash collected is 30M pounds of trash that won’t come face to face with whales, dolphins, seabirds and other beloved wildlife, and that won’t keep breaking down into smaller and smaller pieces, ending up on our dinner plates. There are a lot of ways you can tackle the problem, and we think cleanups are complementary so long as they’re not excuses for delay. By reaching a billion people through #TeamSeas videos, and activating new generations of ocean advocates, we hope to inspire a movement and demand for solutions. Plastic and our oceans don’t mix, and we’re here to do something about it.

* * *

#### WHAT ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE?

Plastic production and climate change are inextricably linked, and both are huge problems for the ocean. Every year, 11 million metric tons of plastics enter our ocean. Nearly all of these plastics are made from fossil fuels including crude oil, natural gas liquids and coal. Ocean Conservancy has estimated that the crude oil needed to make that much plastic is over 800 times more than the amount spilled during the Exxon Valdez disaster! And the greenhouse gas emissions from the plastics sector are about 2 gigatons, equivalent to the emissions of 370 million passenger cars. You can learn more about the plastics-climate connection [here](https://oceanconservancy.org/blog/2021/09/24/plastic-pollution-oil-spill/). There’s much more we need to do to tackle the climate crisis, and we hope you bring this same #TeamSeas energy to other efforts to protect the ocean and the planet.

### CONTACT US

Name \* 

Email Address \* 

Subject \* Select a subject

Message \*

_\* indicates a required field_

SUBMIT

### PRESS INQUIRIES

Name \* 

Company or Organization \* 

Email Address \* 

Phone 

Message \*

_\* indicates a required field_

SUBMIT

**Unsupported Browser!** This website will offer limited functionality in this browser. We only support the recent versions of major browsers like Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and Edge.
